Daniel Coxon

Phone: 085-286-4262 Email: dancoxon37@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/dancoxonprofile

SUMMARY

Developed many systems and programs since starting college using Java as a main coding language. Also, designed and developed many web based applications using HTML, CSS and the JavaPlay Framework. Interested in increasing knowledge on the use of data in real world applications. Ambitious to gain experience in work environments, putting these skills to practice and to continue learning.

IT SKILLS

- Confident user of Java using Netbeans IDE
- · Can design software based on specification using UML
- Can design and create database schemas
- Capable of designing developing websites using Java Play Framework, JavaScript, CSS HTML and Twitter Bootstrap, Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ IDEA
- Competent user of Windows and Windows Command Prompt
- Design build and troubleshoot a network using routers in Cisco Packet Tracer
- Configure a router using the Cisco IOS command set

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

2015 - 2019 BSc (Hons) Computing

Institute of Technology Tallaght, Dublin 24

2nd Year: GPA: 2.88

| ar. Or A. 2.00 | | | | | | | |
|----------------|--------------------------------------|------------|-----------------------------------|----|---|--|--|
| | Discrete Mathematics 2 | A | Information Security | B+ | 1 | | |
| | Web & Mobile Design & Development | B + | Networking 2 | В | | | |
| | Software Quality Assurance & Testing | В | 2 nd Year Project | B- | | | |
| | Networking 1 | В | Management Science | B- | | | |
| | Software Development 3 | C+ | Software Development 4 | C+ | | | |
| | Database Design & Programming | C | Object Oriented Analysis & Design | C | | | |

1st Year: GPA: 3.21

| • • | | | | | | | |
|-----|--|----|----------------------------------|--------------|---|--|--|
| | Learning to learn at 3 rd level | B+ | Object Oriented Systems Analysis | A | 1 | | |
| | Discrete Mathematics 1 | B+ | Operating System Fundamentals | B + | | | |
| | Business Information Systems | B+ | Software Development 2 | B + | | | |
| | Software Development | B+ | Database Fundamentals | В | l | | |
| | Fundamentals of Interface Web Design | B- | Social Media Communications | В | | | |
| | Computer Architecture | B- | Statistics | \mathbf{C} | | | |

2013 - 2015 HND in Contemporary Music Performance.

Ballyfermot College of Further Education, Dublin 10

2013 - Leaving Certificate

Holy Family Community School, Rathcoole, Dublin.

Significant Projects Undertaken

2nd Year Group Project

A web based cinema ticket booking system using the Javaplay framework. The system allowed users to browse films in our database, view showing times, trailers and ratings, create an account of their own to log in and purchase virtual cinema tickets. As the developers, we had administrator access which allowed us to log in, create, update and delete films/showing times from the database.

Challenges faced & overcome

- Working with different database relationships and bug fixing
- Team communication

Technologies & Tools Used:

Javaplay framework, Java, IntelliJ idea, HTML & CSS, Bootstrap, UML

WORK EXPERIENCE

June 2016 – Present Musician

- Playing gigs in various venues around Dublin
- Crowd interaction/entertainment

May 2015 – June 2016 Restaurant Staff An Poitin Stil

- Working in fast paced high stress kitchen environment
- Liaising directly with chefs/management
- · Serving customers in the restaurant.

INTERESTS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Sporting

 Member of club and school basketball team from 2005 – 2013. Participated in and won many tournaments around Ireland.

Musical

Placed first in multiple music competitions around the country and currently using my talent and
qualification as a part time job. Have also used this skill to travel and work. For example, summer of
2016 was spent living in Spain and supporting myself by playing multiple gigs throughout the weeks
there, meeting many different people and enjoying the experience.

Posts of responsibility

 Volunteer member of the local youth club, helping to organize and participate in many events over the years including trips to Peamount Hospital where we did musical performances and weekends away to Glendalough and Wales. 2007 – 2012.

REFERENCES

Available on request